Daniel Mañá | Full-stack Developer

About

Full-stack Web Developer with extensive Video Streaming knowledge. Worked for few years as a Scrum Master and implemented several start-up MVPs applying the Lean Startup strategy.

Phone: +48 570 000 381

Email: daniel81bcn@gmail.com (mailto:daniel81bcn@gmail.com) LinkedIn: daniel81bcn (http://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel81bcn) github: daniel81bcn (https://www.github.com/daniel81bcn)

bitbucket: daniel81bcn (https://bitbucket.org/daniel81bcn/profile/teams)

Work Experience

Flumotion

2014 - Present

Freelance Full-stack Developer Adding features to the Online Video Platform.

http://flumotion.com (http://flumotion.com)

- Yeoman, Angular JS, JW Player, Video. js, Bootstrap, Material Design.
- Python Django REST Framework.

YadaZing

2014 - 2014

2011 - 2014

Freelance Front-end Engineer Created English lessons using Youtube videos.

http://yadazing.com (http://yadazing.com)

- Yeoman, AngularJS, Video.js, Bootstrap.
- Youtube API, Heap Analytics, Intercom.

Flumotion

Front-end Engineer Developed extensive front-end solutions for the Online Video & Radio Platform.

http://flumotion.com (http://flumotion.com)

- Yeoman, Require.js, AngularJS, Backbone.js, ActionScript, Bootstrap.
- Strobe Media Playback, Video.js, VAST.
- Node.js, Python Django REST Framework, MySQL, Nginx.

Medistream.tv

2014 - 2014

Freelance Full-stack Developer

https://github.com/daniel81bcn/medistream (https://github.com/daniel81bcn/medistream) Developed the first MVP of the product and added some functionality.

- Yeoman, AngularJS, Bootstrap, Stripe.
- Node.js, Python Django REST Framework, MongoDB, MySQL, Nginx.

NicePeopleAtWork

2014 - 2014

Freelance Android Developer Developed a plugin for Android video players to track viewers experience.

http://nicepeopleatwork.com (http://nicepeopleatwork.com)

• Android Development, Widevine.

Wuaki.tv 2012 - 2013

Freelance Flash Developer I18n and analytics service integration.

http://wuaki.tv (http://wuaki.tv)

• ActionScript, Strobe Media Playback 1.6, OSMF 2.0, Conviva.

Flumotion 2010 - 2011

Flex Developer
Designed and developed CMS for the WebTV Online
Video & Radio Platform.

http://flumotion.com (http://flumotion.com)

• Flex, Swiz Framework, Flash CS5.5, Python - Django.

CASER 2008 - 2009

Project Manager and Full-stack Developer Managed 4 developers and worked together implementing an Insurance Solution for the automotive industry. http://caser.es (http://caser.es)

- Flex, Cairngorm, BlazeDS.
- Java 5, JDBC, Oracle, WebLogic 10.1.

Software Greenhouse

2008 - 2008

Web Developer http://swgreenhouse.com (http://swgreenhouse.com)
Analysed, designed and developed new features for several distributed applications for work management.

• J2EE, Struts, Java 5, Hibernate 3.0, SQLServer, Tomcat 6.

Software Greenhouse

2007 - 2008

Freelance Full-stack Developer http://swgreenhouse.com (http://swgreenhouse.com)
Developed an eCommerce store including architecture design, documentation, testing and deployment.

• J2EE, Struts, Java 5, Hibernate 3, MySQL, Tomcat 6.

Nestle 2007 - 2007

Software Developer http://nestle.com (http://nestle.com)
Developed a module to interface between various document templates and unify formats and methodologies among the various departments.

• Crystal Reports, .NET, J#, Acces, Excel.

CCRTV Interactiva

2004 - 2007

System Manager and Software Developer http://www.ccma.cat (http://www.ccma.cat) Maintenance of several multimedia and digital video projects, created cronjobs for scheduled FTP and Terrestrial Digital Television applications updating (TDT - TV3i), and monitored systems and teletext subtitling. 200.000+ registered users.

• J2EE, Struts, Java 1.4 - 5, JDBC, Oracle, Tomcat 5.5 - 6, Nagios, Linux shell scripting.

Forum Barcelona 2004

2004 - 2004

Audiovisual Technician http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2004_Universal_Forum_of_Cultures (http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2004_Universal_Forum_of_Cultures)

Education

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya

2005 - 2006

IT, Thesis

- lava
- Java3D-OpenGL
- MVC Architecture

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya

2000 - 2006

IT, Bachelor's degree

Skills

Methodologies

Master

- Scrum
- Kanban
- Lean Startup

Architecture

Master

- Yeoman
- Require.js
- Grunt
- Gulp
- Bower

UI/UX Design

Master

- Bootstrap
- Material Design
- Font Awesome
- SASS
- LESS

• Front-end Development

Master

- ¡Query
- AngularJS
- Backbone.js
- ActionScript
- Cross-browser development
- Karma
- Protractor

Back-end Development

Advanced

- Node.js
- Python
- Django REST Framework
- Java
- RESTful APIs

Data Modeling

Intermediate

- MySQL
- MongoDB
- PL/SQL
- Django-South
- Hibernate

Server and Hosting Environment Intermediate

- Linux Shell Scripting
- Apache
- Nginx
- Heroku

Languages

Full professional proficiency English

 Spanish Native speaker

 Catalan Native speaker